The notion that we live in someone else’s video game is irresistible to many.
认为我们生活在别人的电子游戏里，这种想法对许多人来说有着难以抗拒的吸引力。
Searching the term “simulation hypothesis” returns numerous results that debate whether the universe is a computer simulation — a concept that some scientists actually take seriously.
搜索“模拟假说”这个词，会得到大量搜索结果，都在争论宇宙是不是计算机模拟——一些科学家确实认真对待这个概念。
Unfortunately, this is not a scientific question.
遗憾的是，这不是一个科学问题。
We will probably never know whether it’s true.
我们很可能永远无从知道这一说法是否属实。
We can, instead, use this idea to advance scientific knowledge.
不过，我们可以转而利用这个想法来推动科学知识的发展。
The 18th-century philosopher Kant argued that the universe ultimately consists of things-in-themselves that are unknowable.
18世纪的哲学家康德认为，宇宙归根结底是由不可知的“物自体”构成的。
While he held the notion that objective reality exists, he said our mind plays a necessary role in structuring and shaping our perceptions.
虽然他持有“客观现实是存在的”这一观点，但他也说，我们的心智在构建和塑造感知的过程中起着必不可少的作用。
Modern sciences have revealed that our perceptual experience of the world is the result of many stages of processing by sensory systems and cognitive functions in the brain.
现代科学已经揭示，我们对世界的感知体验，是大脑中的感觉系统和认知功能经过许多阶段处理的结果。
No one knows exactly what happens within this black box.
没有人确切知道这个黑箱里发生了什么。
If empirical experience fails to reveal reality, reasoning won’t reveal reality either since it relies on concepts and words that are contingent on our social, cultural and psychological histories.
如果实证经验无法揭示现实，那么推理也同样无法揭示现实，因为推理所依赖的概念和词语，取决于我们在社会、文化和心理方面的经历。
Again, a black box.
又是一个黑箱。
So, if we accept that the universe is unknowable, we also accept we will never know if we live in a computer simulation.
所以，如果我们接受宇宙不可知，也就接受了：我们永远不会知道自己是否生活在计算机模拟之中。
And then, we can shift our inquiry from “Is the universe a computer simulation?” to “Can we model the universe as a computer simulation?”
这样一来，我们就可以把探究的问题从“宇宙是计算机模拟吗？”转向“我们能否把宇宙建模为计算机模拟？”
Modelling reality is what we do.
为现实建模，本来就是我们一直在做的事。
To facilitate our comprehension of the world, we build models based on conceptual metaphors that are familiar to us.
为了便于理解世界，我们以自己熟悉的概念隐喻为基础来构建模型。
In Newton’s era, we imagined the universe as a clock.
在牛顿的时代，我们把宇宙想象成一座时钟。
In Einstein’s, we uncovered the standard model of particle physics.
在爱因斯坦的时代，我们发现了粒子物理学的标准模型。
Now that we are in the information age, we have new concepts such as the computer, information processing, virtual reality, and simulation.
由于如今身处信息时代，我们有了诸如计算机、信息处理、虚拟现实和模拟这样的新概念。
Unsurprisingly, these new concepts inspire us to build new models of the universe.
不出所料，这些新概念启发我们构建新的宇宙模型。
Models are not the reality, however.
然而，模型并不是现实。
There is no point in arguing whether the universe is a clock, a set of particles or an output of computation.
争论宇宙是一座时钟、一组粒子还是计算的产物，是没有意义的。
All these models are tools to deal with the unknown and to make discoveries.
所有这些模型都是用来应对未知、有所发现的工具。
And the more tools we have, the more effective and insightful we can become.
而且，我们拥有的工具越多，就能变得越高效、越有洞察力。
It can be imagined that, comparable to the process of building previous scientific models, developing the “computer simulation” metaphor-based model will also be a hugely rewarding exercise.
可以想象，与以往构建科学模型的过程相似，开发基于“计算机模拟”这一隐喻的模型也将是一项回报极大的工作。